A Finding Aid to the Alfred Victor Frankenstein Papers, 1875-1985, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Personal Business Records, 1956-1977; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 6 Folders Box 14
  - Appraisal, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Employment Records, 1957-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Estate Records, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Receipts, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25-26)
  - Vehicle Records, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Printed Material and Commercial Sound Recordings, 1889-1985; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 14-17, 21
  Printed materials include clippings, copies of congressional resolutions, exhibition announcements and catalogs, issues of magazines and periodicals, museum bulletins, and blank postcards. Also found are eight commercial audio recordings, likely of music, however, a cassette entitled Heritage of American Art may be related to the exhibition of the same name at the Metropolitan Museum of Art in 1975. Medical conference materials may have belonged to Frankenstein's father.
  - Clippings, 1940s-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1892-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
  - Congressional Materials, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1900-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7-14)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1950s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1-9)
  - Heritage of American Art, 1970s; Archival Resource Key; 1 Cassette tape (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Magazines and Periodicals, circa 1900-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11-18)
  - Magazines and Periodicals, circa 1900-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    Oversized material housed in Box 21, Folder 4-5
  - Medical Conference Materials, 1897-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Museum Bulletins and Guides, 1930s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Phonograph Records, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key; 6 Sound recordings (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Postcards, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Audio Recording, Charles Ives, 2nd Piano Sonata, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound recording 1.5ml Acetate Reel (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Magazines and Periodicals, from Box 17, F2, 1889-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
- Photographs, circa 1940-circa 1970; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 17-21
  Photographic material includes black and white and color photographs, copy prints, contact sheets, negatives, slides, and transparencies. There are snapshots and portraits of Alfred Victor Frankenstein and his family, and photocopies of a family photograph album. A majority of the photographs are of artwork by nineteenth and twentieth century artists and were compiled by Frankenstein as part of his research. Additional photographs of works of art may be found in Series 4.
  - Family Photo Album, Photocopy, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Alfred Victor Frankenstein and Family, circa 1940-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
    - Architecture, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Cartoon, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Drawings and Sketches, by Viktor Aleksandrovich Gartman, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Iconography, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Illustrations, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Landscapes, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Modern and Post-Modern Art, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
    - Paintings, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18-21)
    - Portraits, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22-23)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
    - Portraits, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1-8)
    - Scenes, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9-11)
    - Sculpture, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Still-Life and Trompe l'Oeil, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13-17)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 19)
    - Unidentified, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 20)
    - Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Oversized, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Unidentified Sound Recordings, circa 1960-circa 1970; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders Box 20
  Found are six cassettes and one sound reel, without additional contextual information to further describe the material.
  - Audio Recording, Reel, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Audio Recording, Cassettes, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key; 6 Cassette tapes (Box 20, Folder 6)